http://www.osec.doc.gov/opog/privacy/default.html

U.S. Department of Commerce, Office of Privacy and Open Government, Privacy ProgramSkip to Navigation   Skip to Main Content.
Privacy Office
Senior Agency Official for Privacy (SAOP)/Chief Privacy Officer (CPO) & Director of Open Government
Deputy Program Director for Privacy and Directives Operations
Deputy Program Director for FOIA/PA and Open Government Operations
Bureau Chief Privacy Officers
Computer Incident Response Teams (CIRTS)
Director of Open Government
Open Government Senior Leaders (OGSL)
The FOIA
Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)
Director, SAOP, Chief Privacy Officer
Deputy Program Director for FOIA/PA and Open Government Operations
Materials Technical Advisory Committee
President's Export Council Subcommittee on Export Administration
Regulations and Procedures Technical Advisory Committee
Sensors and Instrumentation Technical Advisory Committee
Transportation and Related Equipment Technical Advisory Committee
Bureau of the Census
Bureau of the Census Scientific Advisory Committee
Census Bureau National Advisory Committee on Racial, Ethnic, Other Populations
International Trade Administration
Office of Energy and Environmental Industries (OEEI)
Industry Trade Advisory Committees
Committee of Chairs of the Industry Trade Advisory Committees
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Aerospace Equipment
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Automotive Equipment and Capital Goods
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Building Materials, Construction, and Nonferrous Metals
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Chemicals, Pharmaceuticals, Health Science Products and Services
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Consumer Goods
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Customs Matters and Trade Facilitation
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Distribution Services
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Energy and Energy Services
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Forest Products
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Information and Communications Technologies, Services, and Electronic Commerce
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Intellectual Property Rights
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Services and Finance
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Small and Minority Business
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Standards and Technical Trade Barriers
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Steel
Industry Trade Advisory Committee on Textiles and Clothing
National Institute of Standards and Technology
Advisory Committee on Earthquake Hazards Reduction
Board of Overseers of the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award
National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration
Advisory Committee for the Sustained National Climate Assessment
U.S. Patent and Trademark
National Medal of Technology and Innovation Nomination Evaluation Committee
Privacy Program
The Privacy Office is responsible for the development and maintenance of privacy policies, procedures, and guidance essential to safeguarding the collection, access, use, dissemination, and storage of personally identifiable information (PII), business identifiable information (BII), and Privacy Act information in accordance with the Privacy Act of 1974, the E-Government Act of 2002, Federal Information Security Modernization Act (FISMA) of 2014, and policy and guidance issued by the President and Office of Management and Budget (OMB).
DEPARTMENT PRIVACY OFFICE
The Department’s Privacy Office
within the Office of the Secretary, Chief Financial Officer and Assistant
Secretary for Administration, Office of Privacy and Open Government.
Senior Agency Official for Privacy (SAOP)/Chief Privacy Officer (CPO)
& Director of Open Government
Deputy Director
Deputy Program Director for Privacy and Directives Operations
Deputy Program Director for FOIA/PA and Open Government Operations
Commerce Privacy Mission Statement
Authority & Responsibilities
Privacy Council
DOC PII Breach Response Task Force
Contact Information
PRIVACY COMPLIANCE
An overview of the Department’s privacy compliance process and related documents, which includes the Privacy Threshold Analysis (PTA) and Privacy Impact Assessments (PIAs).
Privacy Threshold Analysis (PTA) Requirement
PTA Template
Privacy Impact Assessment (PIA) Requirement
PIA Template
PIA Annual Review Recertification Form
PIA Process Flowchart
PIA Brochure
Privacy Impact Assessments by Bureau/Operating Unit
National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) PIAs
identifiable information (PII) and business identifiable information (BII).
General privacy laws, Office of Management and Budget (OMB) privacy
policies and guidance, Departmental policies, and bureau/operating unit privacy
policies.
General Privacy Laws Governing Federal Agencies
Office of Management and Budget (OMB)
the Department's information handling practices.
Bureau/Operating Units Third-Party Websites, Applications, and Digital
Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Privacy Policy
National Institute of Standards and Technology Privacy Policy
National Technical Information Service Privacy Policy
National Telecommunications and Information Administration Privacy Policy
Office of Inspector General Privacy Policy
US Patent
and Trademark (USPTO) Privacy Policy and Terms of Use for USPTO Websites
RESOURCES
Additional
privacy resources including contact information, privacy-related templates and brochures,
breach response and notification plan, and System of Records Notices (SORNs).
Bureau Chief Privacy Officers
Computer Incident Response Teams (CIRTS)
System of Records Notices (SORN)
Privacy Act
Back to Top
TRAINING
Privacy training opportunities.
List of current privacy classes coming soon
REPORTS
Privacy-related reports.
Coming Soon
FAQ
Frequently asked questions and factual information about the website.
What is a truncated Social Security
number (SSN)?
Can sensitive PII be sent by
facsimile?
How do I mail sensitive PII?
Back to Top
Questions and Comments
Send Questions,
Comments or Complaints on the Commerce Privacy
program to CPO@doc.gov.
Office of Privacy and Open Government
Office of the Chief Financial Officer and Assistant Secretary for Administration
U.S. Department of Commerce
Page last updated:
